PRITHVIRAJ MODY

Student - Computer Science Major



CONTACT

- 530-979-3451
- ✓ prithvirajmody@gmail.com
- https://prithviraj-mody.web.app/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/prithviraj-mody/
- https://github.com/prithvirajmody

EDUCATION

University of California Davis

2024 - Present Computer Science Major

Dhirubhai Ambani International School

2022 - 2024

International Baccalaureate Diploma Program

The Cathedral and John Connon School

2011 - 2022 ICSE and IGCSE

SKILLS

- Python, Java, C++, JavaScript
- Al, Machine Learning and Data Analysis
- Critical thinking and research skills
- Leadership and project coordination
- Organization and time management skills
- Quick learner

CODING PROJECTS

- Voice enabled virtual assistant
- Image classification Al
- Computer Vision Al
- Command line encryption tool
- Small business order management system
- SMS text classification project

PROFILE

I am an experienced programmer, with a passion for creating coding projects to help others. I know how to code in multiple languages and can use both Windows and Linux operating systems. I am familiar with several types of AI algorithms and advanced data structures. I have previous experience through internships, independent coding projects and other collaborative efforts. Furthermore, I am a quick and dedicated learner who is willing and able to pick up on new skills incredibly efficiently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INTERN

Rubik's Data Science

June 2023 - July 2023

During this internship, I researched and evaluated multiple machine learning algorithms, narrowing down to 15 key models and neural networks for detecting commercial credit risk, using Al. Also, I presented a detailed study of the pros and cons of each of the models to the CTO, providing strategic insights for decision-making.

INTERN

Cyware Labs

July 2022 - August 2022

In this internship, I implemented an automated system to assess viral load and malware risk in files, ensuring the safety of both files and devices

INTERN

Employee at Axis Bank

June 2022 - July 2022

I Interned under the ex-AVP of Axis Bank. In this internship, I developed a web scraper to retrieve stock price data from a website and automated information processing workflows.

^{*}See GitHub profile for details